



# Sophia Abolore

Toronto Ontario 204-510-8356 sophiaabolore@gmail.com

I m a first year computer science student at the University of Toronto planning on focusing in artificial intelligence research and engineering. I m currently employed at Manrex, a pharmaceutical device production company as a part time Software developer. I have three years of experience programming in Java and Python as well as a couple years of experience in Web development through Wordpress and HTML, CSS and Javascript as well as iOS development with Swift. I m familiar with building Machine Learning models with tensor flow and working with SQL databases. I m really passionate about ethics in the tech industry and have experience working on the social responsibility reports for autonomous vehicles. I'm fluent in English can also communicate in four additional languages including Yoruba, French, Spanish and Arabic.

# **Work Experience**



# **Software Developer**

07/2020 to Present

Manrex Limited

Toronto Ontario

(Returning position after internship)

- Planning and development of an IOS application.
- · Object detection with Tensorflow machine learning models
- · App development with Swift

### **Systems Team Member**

08/2020 to Present

aUToronto

University of Toronto

(Competitive autonomous vehicle development group)

- Writing reports for the competition
- Designing and documenting system architecture and interfaces
- Developing integrated tests with other sub-team
- Delivering high quality pitches and presentations to judges
- Working with ROS, C++, Python and robotics systems

## **Software Development Intern**

07/2020 to 09/2020

Manrex Limited

Winnipeg Manitoba

(Pharmaceutical device development company)

· Building an easy to navigate website.

- Designing and developing an app.
- · Creating templates for landing pages social media, mail-outs and digital board advertisements.
- Creating forms/ algorithms for new and existing websites.
- Assisting staff with creating advertisements for digital ads.
- Developing promotional materials.
- · Teaching staff to use the templates for after summer terms are over.
- · Assisting staff with any technical issues.

# Parliamentary Secretary to the Minister of Public Relations

07/2020 to Present

Youth Parliament of Manitoba

Winnipeg Manitoba

(Volunteer led program for youth interested in politics and public policy)

- Promoting YPM s activities to the community;
- · Greeting and handling the media during
- Session; Managing YPM s Twitter, Facebook, Instagram accounts, and blogs.
- · Planning and organizing press conferences.

#### Teen Ambassador

09/2019 to 07/2020

Canada Learning Code

Winnipeg Manitoba

(Organization that aims to help everyday Canadians learn to code)

- Organize 5 meetups to run and lead coding learning experiences
- Commit to and attend 4-8 monthly Zoom: Online Meetups
- · Write and submit 2 blog posts
- Attend local events to gain exposure to the technology industry
- · Help promote CLC experiences happening in your community (ie. Code Mobiles, Chapters, Signature Events, etc.)

## **Programming and Robotics Facilitator**

10/2018 to 01/2020

CanU

Winnipeg Manitoba

(Organization that aims to promote confidence and learning opportunities for kids)

- Teaching 5th and 6th graders how to code.
- Coordinating Robotics classes for 7th-10th grade students.
- Debugging and explaining complex concepts.
- · Planning lessons and setting up the laboratory.

## **Personal Projects**

09/2016 to Present

#### Upside:

A mental health focused website for teens and young adults to navigate commonly experienced negative emotions and effectively deal with them. The website will be launched later in the year and contains a dashboard with a daily quiz that tracks the resilience of the user, provides scientific information about what happens to the brain and body when they re experiencing different emotions and methods to cope with them.

## Marvel vs. DC Galaxy game:

An 80's like video game in which characters from the marvel universe battle those from DC universe while orbiting in space.

## Object counter app:

An iOS application that uses object detection through tensor flow and yolov4 to return the number of a specified object in a photograph.

#### **Achievements**

- University of Toronto National Scholarship recipient and Scholar.
- Lifetouch Humanities Award recipient.
- CanU Lead Award Recipient.
- Jeanneret Executive President.
- Member of the first place winner's of 2020 Auto Drive competition (Autoronto).
- Ethics Bowl Competitor.
- TD Scholarship semi-finalist.
- Pandora Poetry Competition First Place Winner.
- Youth Parliament Cabinet Member.
- Voices for Change Founder and Facilitator.
- Female Engineer focus group coordinator.
- · Upside Founder and Developer.
- Habitat for Humanity Club Co-leader.
- Professor Sheila McIlraith Mentee.
- Diana Carrier Mentee.
- DisruptEd Conference speaker.

## Skills



Python - 3 years

Java - 3 years

Swift - 2 years

Wordpress - 1 year

HTML, CSS and Javascript - 2 years

Public Speaking - 4 years

Machine Learning - 1 year

Teaching Computer Programming - 3 years

Social Media Management - 1 year

Leadership - 2 years

Slam Poetry - 2 years

Musical Performance - 6 years

# **Education**



# **University of Toronto**

Bachelor's

Computer Science

Toronto Ontario

09/2020 to Present

# Links



https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophia-abolore-763a06168/?

lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad\_flagship3\_resumebuilder%3BA3ciMGnqSQKalZkhi82

K1g%3D%3D

https://github.com/sophiaabolore